healthaffairs.org 2019-03-30

# Privacy Policy | Health Affairs

**Privacy Policy**  
Last updated: May 25, 2018 

**General**  
_Health Affairs_  is published by Project HOPE -- the People-to-People Health Foundation, Inc. We are committed to maintaining your confidence with respect to the privacy of the information we collect from you. This policy outlines how we collect, use and share your personal information that is collected when you visit the  _Health Affairs_  web site, mobile sites, or other online service (“Services”). This privacy policy does not apply to or govern information furnished to Health Affairs through any other means.

**Information We Collect**  
_User Provided Information._  If you are subscriber, register to use the Services, ask for notifications by email, or purchase content you may be required to provide contact information such as name, email address, postal address, and telephone number; password; professional background and educational information, and interests.  If you are purchasing content or services, you will also be asked for credit card information.  In some instances you may provide comments, feedback, and posts to content on the web site. You may choose not to provide us with certain types of information but doing so may affect your ability to use the Services.

_Information Collected Automatically._  We may collect information about your use of the Services to measure and analyze traffic and usage. This can include your IP address; device connection information including browser, operating system, platform, and other unique identifiers used to access the Services; usage information such time and date of use, duration of use, searches, files downloaded and viewed, and other information regarding your interaction with the content; and location information such as the location of your device in order to provide relevant content for where you are in the world. 

**Cookies**  
We use cookies to collect information and help personalize your user experience. We store a minimal amount of personally identify information to protect this information.  Cookies allow us to recognize you when you return to the Services and help us personalize your experience.  We also may use cookies and other tracking technology to track and delivery relevant ads through the Services. 

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but can be configured not to or to notify you when a cookie is being sent. If you wish to disable cookies, refer to your browser help menu to learn how. If you disable cookies, doing so may interfere with or prevent the proper function of a Service.

**Use of Information**  
Information you provide to us will be used to process, fulfill, and deliver your requests for content and services.  We may also use the information to respond to your questions or provide notifications regarding changes; and offer you customized content to make the Services more relevant to your needs. We may also send you information about our various products and services unless you indicate that you do not want to receive such information. You are welcome to unsubscribe from these email services at any time. 

Information collected automatically is used to monitor user’s interests and usage patterns in order to help us enhance and improve our products and services. 

We may share your personal information with applicable third-party service providers such as credit card processors, vendor hosting services, or customer support providers. These third-party organizations are obligated to maintain the confidentiality of your personal information and use it only as necessary to perform their tasks.  We will only report aggregate information about usage to third parties including service providers and advertisers. 

**Email Communications** ****  
Health Affairs publishes electronic newsletters and sends announcements with event or product offerings that we think may be of interest on behalf of partners. These communications must be opted into when registering for this website or by filling in the form for Newletter Signup under the main menu.  Any data we gather about email communications behavior (such as opens and clicks) is used only to help us send you the most relevant communications. 

Health Affairs does not provide, sell, or rent email addresses or other communications data to anyone outside the organization.

You may opt out of receiving certain promotional, non-contractual communications from us at any time by clicking on the opt-out or “unsubscribe” link included in the e-mails you receive. Please note that your opt-out is limited to the e-mail address used and will not affect subsequent subscriptions. Opt-out requests for e-mail may take up to 10 business days to be effective. Your opt-out request will not apply to emails that are transactional, contractual or are not commercial in nature. 

**Advertisers**  
_Health Affairs_  sells advertising to third-parties through our Services.  These advertisements may link to web sites not under our control.  Please be aware that these third party advertisers may use cookie or tracking technology to measure the effectiveness of their ads or collect personally identifying information while you are accessing their digital environment. The privacy policies of that third party may differ from ours, so we encourage you to review them.  _Health Affairs_  is not responsible or liable for any content, advertising, products, or material offered from advertisers or their agents.   _Health Affairs_  is also not responsible for any transaction between you and the third-party. 

**Security Measures**  
_Health Affairs_  attempts to safeguard your personal information against loss, theft, misuse, unauthorized access, or destruction through the use of commercially reasonable administrative, physical and technical security measures. No security system is impenetrable, so we cannot guarantee the security of electronic data nor can we guarantee that the information you supply will not be intercepted.

**Access and Accuracy of Your Information**  
Registered users can access their account information and make corrections or updates after logging into their account. The accuracy of the information is the responsibility of the user. If you choose to stop receiving the newsletter or marketing communications from us, use the “unsubscribe” feature within the communication.   
You may also contact our Customer Service Department by the following:

  * Feedback page
  * Telephone: 301-347-3933
  * Email: [Customerservice@healthaffairs.org](mailto:Customerservice@healthaffairs.org)
  * Mail: Customer Service, Health Affairs, 7500 Old Georgetown Road, Bethesda, MD 20814, USA.

**Compliance with Legal Process**  
When required or permitted by law, we may disclose personally identifying information to (1) comply with the law or legal process; (2) protect the rights and property of ProjectHOPE/Health Affairs; (3) protect against misuse or the unauthorized use of a Service; or (4) protect the personal safety or property of our employees, users, donors, or others.

**Cross-Border Transfer of Your Information**  
The Services are headquartered in the United States. Your personal information may be transferred outside of your country of residence to the United States or another country for processing. By using a Service, you consent to the collection, international transfer, storage, and processing of your information outside of your country of residence, in which case the personal data protection rules may differ from the rules in your country. 

**Children**  
The Services are not intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect or store any personal information from children under 13.

**Changes to This Policy**  
This privacy policy may be periodically updated. We will post a notice that this policy has been amended by revising the “Last updated” date at the top of this page. Use of a Service constitutes consent to any policy then in effect.

_Additional Privacy Information for Users in the EU_

Below is additional information as required by the EU General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”). Please make sure you also consult our general privacy policy above for complete information.

**Controller**

  * The data controller for the Services is: Attn: Data Controller, ProjectHOPE, 7500 Old Georgetown Road, Bethesda, MD 20814, USA. Email: information@healthaffairs.org.

  **Data Protection Officer**

  * You can contact our Data Protection Officer at: Attn: Data Protection Officer, ProjectHOPE, 7500 Old Georgetown Road, Bethesda, MD 20814, USA. Email: information@healthaffairs.org

**Representative in the EU**   
Contact [information@healthaffairs.org](mailto:information@healthaffairs.org),

**Additional Information about Processing of Personal Data**   
Health will process your personal data as it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party, or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract on the basis of your express and voluntary consent in order to comply with a legal obligation to which Health Affairs is subject; or as otherwise permitted by applicable law.

Processing for or Prior to Entering into a Contract

In most cases processing of your personal data will be on this legal basis. For details on which categories of personal data, from which sources and for which purposes your information may be collected and used in relation to which services or products offered by Health Affairs, please refer to the general privacy policy above.

Processing on the Basis of Your Consent

In some situations, and for some Services or application we may ask you to provide express, voluntary consent as a basis for processing your personal information. For details on which categories of personal data, from which sources and for which purposes your information may be collected and used in relation to which services or products offered by Health Affairs, please refer to the information in the general privacy policy above.

You may at any time revoke a consent granted hereunder in accordance with GDPR. In case of revocation, Health Affairs will not process the personal data subject to this consent any longer unless legally required to do so. However, any revocation of your consent has by law no effect on past processing of personal data by Health Affairs up to the point in time of your revocation. Furthermore, if your use of a Service, requires your consent, Health Affairs will no longer able to provide the relevant Service to you after your revocation.

In Order to Comply with a Legal Obligation

In some cases, we must process data to comply with a legal obligation. In such instances our processing of relevant data will be restricted to what is required to fulfil our legal obligations.

Aggregated Anonymous or Pseudonymous Use of Data

Please see the general privacy policy above and our cookie policy for more detailed information.

Duration of Processing of Personal Data 

Personal data processed as permitted by law or under your consent will be stored (i) only for as long as is required to fulfill the respective purposes or (ii) until you revoke your consent. However, when Health Affairs is required by mandatory law to retain your personal data longer or where your personal data is required for Health Affairs to assert or defend against legal claims, we will retain your personal data, in accordance with applicable law, until the end of the relevant retention period or until the claims in question have been settled.

Location of Data Processing

Health Affairs is based in the United States, but operates internationally. Therefore, when Health Affairs uses or otherwise processes your personal data for the purposes set out in its privacy policies, your data may be collected from, processed, or transferred to a country outside of the EU or European Economic Area (“EEA”).

No Decisions Based Solely on Automated Processing

Processing of your personal data does not involve decisions based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produce legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you.

**Data Subject’s Rights under GDPR**

Data Access, Correction and Deletion Right

You can request information about which personal data Health Affairs processes about you and the correction or deletion of such personal data at any time.

Please note that Health Affairs can delete your personal data only if there is no legal or contractual obligation or prevailing right of Health Affairs to retain it. Please also note that if you request that Health Affairs delete your personal data, you will not be able to continue to use a Service that requires use of your personal data.

If Health Affairs uses your personal data based on your consent, or to perform a contract with you, you may also request a copy of the personal data that you have provided to Health Affairs. Please contact Health Affairs’ Data Protection Officer and specify the information or processing activities to which your request relates, the format in which you would like this information, and whether the personal data is to be sent to you or another recipient. Please also provide reasonable information and evidence that permits Health Affairs that the request originates from you as the data subject entitled to receive such personal information and that no one else is abusively trying to access your personal data by requesting a copy of it.

You can also request that Health Affairs restricts your personal data from any further processing for the following reasons: (i) you state that the personal data Health Affairs has about you is incorrect, (but only for as long as Health Affairs requires to check the accuracy of the relevant personal data), (ii) there is no legal basis for Health Affairs processing your personal data and you demand that Health Affairs restricts your personal data from further processing, (iii) Health Affairs no longer requires your personal data, but you claim that you require Health Affairs to retain such data in order to claim or exercise legal rights or to defend against third party claims or (iv) in case you object to the processing of your personal data by Health Affairs (based on Health Affairs’ legitimate interest as further set out in Art. 6 (1) (f) GDPR) for as long as it is required to review as to whether Health Affairs has a prevailing interest or legal obligation in processing your personal data.

Right to Lodge a Complaint

If you believe Health Affairs is not processing your personal data in accordance with applicable EU/EEA data protection laws, you can at any time lodge a complaint with the data protection authority of the EU/EEA member state in which you live or with the data protection authority of Maryland, USA.
